OK so we've talked about why we might have a debate and we've discussed some of the roles of the debate
好的，所以我们已经讨论了为什么我们可能会进行辩论，并且我们已经讨论了辩论的一些角色
and some of the different the different words related to having a debate.
以及一些与辩论相关的不同词语。
OK let's now talk about some of the phrases we can use in the debate itself.
好的，现在让我们谈谈我们可以在辩论本身中使用的一些短语。
And we're going to look at phrases for how we can poke holes in a case.
我们将研究如何在案件中戳洞的短语。
What does that mean.
这意味着什么。
Well as I said before when you have a debate you build a case for something right.
正如我之前所说，当您进行辩论时，您会为正确的事情建立一个案例。
This is my case.
这是我的情况。
I'm making a case for whatever it is.
不管它是什么，我都在为它辩护。
Maybe we're talking about the drinking age here to poke holes in that is to show where the weak points
也许我们在这里谈论饮酒年龄是为了戳洞，这是为了表明弱点在哪里
are and make it look weaker.
是并使它看起来更弱。
On the other side imagine you have a bag full of water and you dig deep dig poke holes in it.
另一方面，想象你有一个装满水的袋子，你在里面挖了很深的洞。
What will happen to the water.
水会怎样。
It will leak out.
它会泄漏出来。
So when we're having a debate one thing we can do is use a couple of specific phrases to show the weaknesses
因此，当我们进行辩论时，我们可以做的一件事是使用几个特定的​​短语来显示弱点
of the other side not the other person but just the arguments being made.
对方不是对方，而只是正在提出的论点。
OK.
好的。
So let's look at how we can do that.
那么让我们看看我们如何做到这一点。
Let me introduce this topic first.
我先介绍一下这个话题。
The drinking age at 21 in the USA is a good way to prevent drinking problems later in life.
在美国，21 岁的饮酒年龄是预防晚年饮酒问题的好方法。
Now I don't know if you know this but in the United States you have to be 21 years or older in order
现在我不知道你是否知道，但在美国你必须年满 21 岁才能
to in order to actually buy alcohol.
为了实际购买酒精。
You say it's the legal drinking age 21 years or older.
你说这是21岁或以上的法定饮酒年龄。
OK.
好的。
Some people say it's a good idea.
有人说这是个好主意。
Some people say it's a bad idea.
有人说这是个坏主意。
It's very controversial.
这是非常有争议的。
OK well it doesn't matter how you feel about it OK.
好吧好吧，不管你怎么想都OK。
But we're not going to focus on your opinion or my opinion but let's just say we're going to disagree
但我们不会专注于您或我的意见，而是说我们会不同意
with this.
有了这个。
We're going to either actually disagree or play the devil's advocate.
我们要么实际上不同意，要么扮演魔鬼的拥护者。
And we're going to look at some phrases we can use.
我们将看一些我们可以使用的短语。
Well one thing we can do is ask a question and we ask a question to force the other side to say yes
好吧，我们可以做的一件事是问一个问题，然后我们问一个问题来迫使对方说是
about something related to a point that is against what they said or against their own argument.
关于与他们所说的或反对他们自己的论点的观点相关的事情。
OK you want to find or pick out true statements small statements that might disagree with their side
好的，您想查找或挑选出真实的陈述 可能不同意他们一方的小陈述
and they should be factual statements.
它们应该是事实陈述。
That means they should be facts F A C.T. s. They should be true.
这意味着它们应该是事实 F A C.T. s。他们应该是真的。
And then the other side has to say yeah that's true.
然后对方不得不说是的，这是真的。
Yes that's true.
是的，这是真的。
Aha yeah that's true.
啊哈是的，这是真的。
And if you make them agree the other side to small points that are smaller than the main argument you
如果你让他们同意另一方的小点，这些小点比你的主要论点更小
force them to do that then it makes their side look weaker.
强迫他们这样做，这会使他们的一方看起来更弱。
This is a very simple thing to do but this is a common debate tactic or strategy.
这是一件非常简单的事情，但这是一种常见的辩论策略或策略。
You can off often use the word tactic.
你可以经常使用战术这个词。
OK so how can we do that.
好的，我们该怎么做。
Well it's very simple and you might see this in movies about court cases where there's a lawyer talking
嗯，这很简单，你可能会在关于法庭案件的电影中看到有律师在说话
to someone in court isn't it true.
对法庭上的某人是不是真的。
Isn't it true.
是不是真的。
Now this is a very powerful beginning because all they have to say to answer this is yes.
现在这是一个非常有力的开始，因为他们只要回答这个问题就可以了。
And if they say no then they have to defend it and say why a fact that you're stating is not true.
如果他们说不，那么他们必须为它辩护并说明为什么你所说的事实是不正确的。
So you should say something that's true.
所以你应该说一些真实的话。
So they have to say yes.
所以他们不得不说是的。
Isn't it true that that many high school students get drunk at least once before age 21.
许多高中生在 21 岁之前至少喝醉一次，这不是真的吗？
Now you have to say yes to that because it is true.
现在你必须对它说“是”，因为它是真的。
There are movies about it.
有关于它的电影。
It's a fact.
这是事实。
Many high school students do get drunk at least some point before they turn 21.
很多高中生至少在他们 21 岁之前喝醉。
It's true.
这是真的。
You have to say yes that's true.
你必须说是的，这是真的。
So I'm building to something maybe I then make another statement like this now isn't it true that blah
所以我正在建立一些东西，也许我现在会做出另一个这样的声明，这不是真的吗？
blah blah.
呸呸呸。
You can make another one.
你可以再做一个。
So I'm slowly breaking down your position your view your case.
所以我正在慢慢打破你的立场，你的观点。
OK.
好的。
Now how about this one.
现在这个怎么样。
And I'm not saying this is a fact.
我并不是说这是事实。
I'm not totally sure.
我不完全确定。
But isn't it true that the rate of alcoholism hasn't decreased over the last 40 years.
但是，酗酒率在过去 40 年没有下降，这不是真的吗？
Now if what you're saying is true the drinking age at 21 is a good idea if what you're saying is true
现在，如果你说的是真的，如果你说的是真的，那么 21 岁的饮酒年龄是个好主意
then we should see that alcoholism or people being addicted to alcohol which is what alcoholism is addicted
那么我们应该看到酗酒或对酒精上瘾的人，这就是酗酒上瘾的原因
to alcohol.
到酒精。
We should see it going down.
我们应该看到它下降。
Right.
正确的。
If it's working.
如果它正在工作。
OK so if I say this isn't it true that the rate of alcoholism hasn't decreased hasn't gone down over
好吧，如果我说这是不是真的酗酒率没有下降并没有下降
the last 40 years maybe I have a graph here.
过去 40 年也许我在这里有一个图表。
Right.
正确的。
As you can see from this graph this is the rate of alcoholism it hasn't gone down.
正如您从这张图表中看到的，这是酒精中毒率并没有下降。
Isn't it true that the rate of alcoholism hasn't gone down over the last 40 years.
酗酒率在过去 40 年里没有下降，这不是真的吗？
The other side has to say.
对方不得不说。
Yeah that's true.
对，是真的。
So this isn't it true thing can be a very very powerful tool when you use it correctly when you ask
所以这不是真的，当你问正确使用它时，它可能是一个非常非常强大的工具
the right questions can't always use it but in many cases you can.
正确的问题不能总是使用它，但在许多情况下你可以。
And I really like it.
我真的很喜欢它。
Now we're going to look at one more question phrase that we can use when we want to show that we believe
现在我们要再看一个疑问句，当我们想要表明我们相信时可以使用它
the other side is wrong and provide an opposite fact.
另一方是错误的，并提供了相反的事实。